DARSHAN SHAH

Software Engineer \diamond MERN Stack \diamond Information Technology Major \diamond India $+91~8320830063 \diamond$ shahdarshanp1999@gmail.com \diamond Linkedin \diamond Github

PROFILE SUMMARY

Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience in full-stack development and collaborated product cycle from conception to completion. Part of a team of 5-10 members through 5+ product launches at a recent experience in a high-growth technology startup.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer VahVah!

Nov 2020 - Present Bangalore, Remote

- Delivered more than 6 Microservices in **Node.js**, **Express.js** and 2 Web Applications in **React.js**, **Next.js**, and **Redux** over a span of 2 years which is deployed on AWS EC2.
- Collaborated with internal teams, including UI/UX designers and QA testers to develop and launch a new Web application with a **90+ SEO** score in 1 month.
- Developed an Admin Panel for internal users to reduce manual work like Easy onboarding process, Assess Homework/Exam, Create Events, etc.
- Aggregated different Shipment Providers and engineered it to a single UI, which decreased manual work for the shipment team around 40%.
- Integrated with Razorpay to build payment flow; Added ability to generate payment link; 2500+ Payments.
- Technologies React, Redux, Next.is, Node.is, Express.is, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis.
- Website https://vahvah.com, https://vahvah.biz

Associate Software Engineer

Nov 2019 - Oct 2020

Ahmedabad

Meditab Software Ltd.

- Designed and implemented web pages to configure two entities in **Angular**.
- Built Authorization module which helps to configure grant to the user.
- Fixed 100+ front-end bugs to improve the quality of software.
- Technologies Angular.

EDUCATION

Vishwakarma Government Engineering College	Ahmedabad, Gujarat
B.E in Information Technology - CGPA: 8.7	May 2016 - Jun 2020
BVD High School Higher Secondary Certificate - Percentage: 91% Secondary School Certificate - Percentage: 86%	Ahmedabad, Gujarat Apr 2014 - Apr 2016 Apr 2013 - Mar 2014

SKILLSET

Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Java

Technology Node.js, Express, React, Redux, Next.js, Angular

Database MySQL, MongoDB, Redis

Platform GitHub Actions, GitLab, AWS(EC2, S3, ECS, SQS), RazorPay, Docker

Additional Skills Data Structures and Algorithms (Certified by HackerRank), Touch Typing (55wpm)

Hobbies Chess, Cricket